there is this one thing I'm dreaming
about and that is we need to find some
damn connection with his arm and all of
us and it was always Sufism is the only
part of his father is really interesting
that connects with the rest the world
and creates the idea of a universal
religion Islam's own claims towards
being a universal a denial fortunately
totally you know deaf and blind to
reality he's just no reciting the Quran
in Arabic like Sufism is absolute key I
think
tantric Buddhism is key Sufism is key we
are we should definitely have some kind
of dialogue with Daoists and we love
experts in Taoism and find that that's
definitely what to connect with the
Chinese there has to be connected we can
did this whole pattern together over the
next say five to ten years so much can
be done what I like about this you're
what you're saying here is it's a world
that you're singing it you know you're
including the whole world you know when
you hear a lot of people are just
talking about the West or something here
well these Peterson and it's always
about tell you what nobody neisha talks
about the West they talk about the East
so I mean with the Chinese with the
Indians we can't sit on heads and the
Americas the West is superior because
it's so it's not it couldn't even keep
his own damn empires together simply
because those empires have built on boys
ambitions of plundering the world know
the civilized 10-person history was the
Persian Empire neither the Mongol Empire
was way better than any of the European
press because the Mongols were
bloodthirsty and they were ruthless
once they conquered all the territory
today they did conquer the competent
model from the best of the Persian of
the Chinese emperors and they created
the libertarian Empire with a low tax
rate and they were actually popular the
reason why the Mongol Empire fell apart
in the 14th century was because of the
plague it wasn't because of a lack of
popularity you can learn a lot from them
we can learn a lot from the person
embarrassed three of them that's for
sure we can certainly learn from the
Chinese Empress too but when it comes to
the short period when England and France
and Holland and Germany and Portugal and
Spain conquer the world and plundering
for humanity and plumy we call that
colonialism it fell apart with the first
world war in a terrible disaster Farakka
speaks very well about this he
understands definitely but the disaster
the Europe became he shortly
failed I want to stop you because I
wanted to keep talking about this
because I have a friend Cordelia fan and
she wanted you to talk about
specifically Europe right for her but we
love her Biden she wants to she wants to
talk about she wants you when she's
doing a she's doing a magazine next next
month on Europe and she specifically
asked me a few times you have to talk
the part about about Europe so where do
we begin and speaking about Europe well
well Europe really needs is a wake-up
call but it has to start with the
rewriting of European history and any
and I don't mean to rewrite it like the
Europeans were the perpetrators of the
world with rapists of the other contents
and all that no it's more like from and
we can more like be in try your opinion
and look inside and just realize the
Empress we created had no functioning
ideology they were basically trade
empires built by a few trading companies
to cynically exploited the world driven
by very boyish infantile fantasies about
conquering the rest of world driven by
racist stupid minutes blatantly untrue
and that's why if you compared to say
the Persian Empire and other persons
set the Jews free in Babylon and asked
them to return to Jerusalem in the
second Exodus to create the nation of
Israel so that could be a model nation
within the Persian Empire now if the
European empires that understood that's
rebuild the program per and authentic in
part you're authentically phallic
instead of the false phallic empires the
Europeans created the plunder of the
world and actually fell apart now they
weren't all bad
you know they we did export the printing
press the rest the world
we eventually export industrialization
the rest of them and finally at the end
of the 20th century the rest of world
was playing catch-up and and you know
people aren't starving on a level they
used to do fifty years ago any longer
and we moved hundreds of millions of
people out of poverty around the world
or at least they have moved themselves
out of poverty to be honest about it but
we had to get around the whole problem
of your income to get there and in this
process your passive found its own soul
again and now when even the British
Empire the last remnants of the British
Empire Britain itself is falling apart
maybe it's time for the Europeans to
wake up you know and realize meant to
read our own history and see Europe as a
part of the world that now has to be an
active living part of the world and not
some kind of dead fort that isolates
itself and go seem to know in economic
downward spiral with only old people in
it and no youth no new fresh ideas no
radical new no radical ideas at all the
only the only guy out there kind of kind
of I like him and that's a man with my
chrome and I might disagree with him on
many points but the damn guy is at least
reforming France and he must be
fiendishly difficult the former
countries France that France is sort of
fallen into its crisis slowly over
decades and become the sort of monolith
that hardly moves slow economic growth
conservatism they don't want to learn
English to know what part of one and you
we love France we understand why because
once you come to France you get served
all those crazy great dinners and you go
to the coast and all that wonderful
climate you know I love the horses so
Normandy and your problem oh that's my
surprise you damned liver me it's a
great country but it's becoming a parrot
of itself and Italy even more so Italy
is now nothing but a postcard that
produces nothing of export value any
longer and it's just a tourist
destination hardly anything else
now that's tragic yeah well I see that
in the arts actually it's like yeah
cinema was very alive and Italy in in
France in the 50s and 60s what
progress of the old institutions that
must die are the strongest in Europe
that means the work is still building
political institutions the European
Union is a really weird construction
that never had much popularity to begin
with maybe just know afterwards don't so
I don't know but ok political
institutions academic institutions
they're terrible Europe they're
underfunded they pack in too many
students they don't teach it about
anything the people still believe in
them it's like the Europeans are so
stuck in the Cartesian mythology of
Europeans of damn brilliant and
civilised and they believe so strongly
these institutions they don't see
anything else the best parts of Europe
to go to are the parts were the oldest
attunes are weakest that's why a lot of
the Baltic states that's what law
Central and Eastern Europe way more than
our Western Europe a much more inspired
in the place like Kiev Ukraine or into
Blazek Georgia today then I would be
inspired in Paris or London because the
more you can get away from Oxford and
Cambridge and so only the old academic
institutions the old political parties
political institutions or France and the
UK the more you can get away from those
systems the more freely you can think
the more digital you can be the more
vertically you can be in your ideas
vertical why look just take it's taking
place like say um Hamburg right it's a
wealthy city no money German is still
runs well they do their stuff well you
know they still make car parts for
Chinese electric cars or whatever but
they still do well exports ok
respectfully so Samberg is one of the
wealthiest cities on the planet but they
don't dare to build anything hi
because they're all conservative and
they were loaned Hamburg is a city where
people are on average 70 years old and
they play golf clubs and they eat french
dinners and you know print things and
they're very conservative they don't
like change they don't want to change
anything and all you think is that why
don't they just go to Dubai and
Singapore and get some damn inspiration
next year then boring old Hamburg
because they're phallic and they have
life to them it's just boring and
Hamburg down this what about Stockholm
it's somewhere in between at least the
great thing with Scandinavia's the
cultures here as young a bit like Canada
right because of Scandinavia are at
least as young as North America because
you know except for it was a Lutheran s
of the Sweden finally right in the mouth
before that yeah they had a brief period
when it was warm in the north in the
Vikings facing the plunder the earth and
digital slave trade with the Russians
and so same trade with the ring but you
know that is short there of the Vikings
but the period when Scandinavia finally
arrived on the map was the period when
Sweden was a superpower and that wasn't
Protestantism needed some bastion
somewhere to build from since that
couldn't be Germany because Germany is
just wrecked into pieces by the thirty
year war it became sweet Scandinavia
right on the map assistance Gandhi has
sort of tried to find his place in the
map but it's a much more youthful that
much more open culture than Central
Europe so changes in Sweden occurring
way faster than they do in France or
Italy sociological changes new new
fashions new ideas are being tried the
lifestyle experiments were doing this
talked about and heard of in the rest of
Europe with the possible exception of
Berlin and Copenhagen nobody cares to
live the kind of lives for livens talk
about the moment this is also
interesting this also points toward the
future so you know but at the end of the
day the future is digital and vertical
it's not horizontal it's not about
territory
it's not about conquering territory and
longer that ended in 1959 it's all
vertical and digital from now on
and I look for anywhere out there were
people dare to build skyscrapers not
knowing dare to do shit that's the place
to go that's where the sexist shit
happens and in places where everybody's
taken to court as soon as to have a new
idea a bad places to be that's what most
of Europe is like today America is
certainly like that today if anybody
asks a new ID in the United States think
about asking you it in Europe people
take you to court and sue you for it the
druggies are courtly stop dirty from
happening and they're all nimbus not in
my backyard
Europe is following me and not to be
devil's advocate but in Russia or
Singapore picnic having new ideas well
in Russia Eagle Eagle falls apart
Russian Brasilia falls apart because of
the corruption of the systems they have
sort of vulgar amateur versions of these
institutions that I'm attacking I'm
basically attacking all these situations
of all the nation-states ironically I
want to save them until you know
something better but I'm attacking the
because of the long run they cannot stay
so we need new institutions we need new
institutions of truth with new
institutions of executive power and we
need new institutions of legislative
power so we we need new institutions
European institution doesn't cut it no
because they're not digital mm-hmm
everything being done in Europe right
now is all about stopping preventing
digital from happening taxing it killing
it mm-hmm Europe doesn't like
genetically modified food will fuck you
it's great York doesn't like nuclear
power because they're a populist and
Angela Merkel is burning coal instead
bad idea Angela you're killing the
planet Angela Merkel is one of the the
worst criminals when it comes to climate
crime ever she closed down the power
plant nuclear power plants in Germany in
turn of the coal plants is that terrible
Angela terrible idea so to be an echo
taupe Ian today you're not going to
Europe to find the solutions you really
don't
that's where Europe is full of
environmentalists and they're not gonna
save the planet
the guys are gonna save the planet are
gonna be South Korean engineers and
they're gonna be people out there in the
world who create the solutions to the
problems so we we the use of technology
and machine intelligence can save the
planet because the machine intelligence
will be told it needs to be our Messiah
and save us amazing need to save the
planet it needs to create prayed and
communication between you being so they
don't kill each other and in order for
that to happen we need to leave Europe
right now it's not happening in Europe
just a total lack of imagination and the
institutional resistance against change
in Europe is enormous and people who
called us as radical are not radical at
all they're basically NIMBYs
environmentalists they call us as green
whatever they're just rasoi and
backward-looking conservatives why are
we still putting our junk in different
boxes that would be the first thing
machine intelligence with cell phones
not everything in one place machine
takes care of it now if the machines in
Europe don't even take care of our own
garbage in 2019 you're so damned behind
on technology they don't see Europe
having any of the solutions to the
climate crisis that has to be mentioned
somewhere else probably India Korea
another place but not a Europe we talk
about dead religion we talk about dead
philosophy we talk about dead culture
yeah hold your death cultural golf
Thompson conservatism that's another
threat that's one of the three the other
two of course the two opponents there
are the resilience today they all try to
those left but the third one oh yeah
conservatism of a rapidly aging society
with screwed demographics where only old
people vote no people have all the power
and old people control politics they
control academia and they control
industry well they're not gonna do
anything to find solutions to the
current problems they're just kind of go
into moralizing become Church ladies and
be tired about terrified of anything new
and of change so we're talking about our
extreme lack of
vitality here Martino the demographic
desk what about the rise of nationalism
and all that and blah blah blah you you
told me that you were you wanted to one
of the things that you wanted to talk
about was why you have public debates
with people on me all right and I did do
two things this wild centric you know
all these people who are journal is a
good expression a good opinion they're
there they're there people who are not
in with good opinion and it occurred to
me that the people I like are almost
never good opinion people right now
exactly because they make a drink what
right yeah and they're often boys from
there alive that's what I like about you
it's like it's like there's something
it's something it's something very alive
which you don't find in good opinion you
find I guess you find this you you said
Marty do you find this cliche and all
these you know just don't find anything
going on so so so I'm so interested in
these wacky people that it you know what
I did do this one thing this summer okay
beginning of the summer I had a debate
in Swedish with the Swedish alright
leader I hope he doesn't mind if I call
that Gustav Cassel strong now so far he
has not succeeded in creating a
parliamentary party in Swedish politics
but the guy's incredibly charismatic in
is an ultra nationalist and I'm sure
he's going to be very successful in
Sweden than twenty twenties all you need
is a little financial crisis you know a
few less jobs out there in Kazakhstan
will be very very up okay I don't wanna
I don't wanna be in anything with this
guy I'd like to be his friend I like to
be in the constant dialogue and
conversation with the guy
it turns out he respects me as a
philosopher so I invited him for a
debate we talk for two and a half hours
in front of a packed auditorium in a
hotel in Stockholm put it online and the
next day there were 100,000 views
24 hours yeah this was during the
european union elections in Sweden not
that he or I were even close to winning
that election anything like that at all
this was by far the debate during the
election campaign that all young sweets
loved the most
okay so why is that okay because it's an
interesting conversation between a
nationalist mr. Costas Trump and
cosmopolitan aesthetics underbar mmm so
what I did was that I honored him for
his nationals who found common ground
during the debate for example that we
live in the middle of a high degree and
existentialist
crisis causes Jonas a big fan of Jordan
Peterson of these guys out there he
understands that we live in the middle
of an existential crisis that
established politics doesn't even deal
with or even less so understands even
worse arrogantly okay so we agreed on
that there's either garyun existential
crisis going on a society people feel
lost there's their the masses Elton
ignorant arrogant elite the desert of
his ass kicked and maybe even has the
shows that its heads chopped off fine we
agreed on that but then I challenged him
and said but the problem with you is
that I believe in founded mission and
what is her found a Christian and
constant couldn't say anything about
what Sweden would be like 50 years from
now except he didn't like the idea that
people who walked on the sea would be
too dissimilar from himself yeah
why do you base that on and then he said
we look at Iceland okay ice understand
our nation stayed for a thousand years
and you know we kept Aryan clean or
whatever I didn't say that you know yes
I study sort of the successful northern
European country and I said well to
begin with it's a very cold part of the
world and hardly anybody of a ghost
there may be that protected Iceland for
a thousand years but if I stunt your
honor eyes them for having been a nation
for a thousand years then Rome has
existed for three thousand years in
Cairo has existed for 5,000 years
yeah got a much better more sustainable
model for the future that's called the
city the world city yeah the
cosmopolitan city that's why I'm a
cosmopolitan list so I believe in
cosmopolitanism simply because it's a
better idea or the National
simply because it's more sustainable
it's better for you and beings to live
in larger cities and be segregated and
have the Chinatown's are the Duke towns
and other person towns or whatever trade
him between these townships and then
create a digital model of God which is
the Internet yeah and then you don't
have to have any territory that's just
transport territory you only need the
territory people actually need to be him
to live and to act now that's the motive
for the internet that's the model for
the city and he admitted that actually I
hadn't found a collision and we're
moving towards a world where everybody
will be connected with everybody else
so they will create a digital world that
definitely Cosmopolis and to this
constant phones we can then attach
cosmopolitan values and then honored him
again and said but listen Gustav you're
right about one thing
we're only tribal the priesthood history
have folders to go from tribe to clan
from crime to nation and it's taken them
thousands of years to fool us into
believing we can be nationalists and
meet people who speak and talk and write
like us and actually share something
with them but now we have to fool people
even one step further they go from
ancient empire and anantadeva said
that's what I'm working on
that's my job as a philosopher is to try
to convince you and your nation could
work within an empire and then I just
said you're not in town to send it to
somebody no no no I like to do survive
great okay that's how the old tractor
actually talked to but I love the
Israelis and I love the Jews and I love
the Palestinians and allow the Jews
precisely because did the ultimate
nationalists and all of the Palestinians
curse to be ultimate cosmic
consciousness nor build Empire
Palestinians are great if you want this
nation do some great so we left it at
that left the rest of the orders to
decide for themselves it went viral the
people went berserk
unfortunately Swedish you have to
understand Swedish dancing but at the
end of the summer I then went for
another guy that's sort of been
chastised and thrown out you know the
margins society who actually think is a
figure of the future and that's Alex
abarkment formerly mostly known as alex
fahrt man-beast is most known as a
lecturer
now this is a very interesting character
in an erogenous character
I heard nothing but bad things about
that's a good sign yeah that's a good
sign if you only hear bad things about
somebody but they're still popular
that means the rock'n'roll and probably
they're onto something okay that's
called crazy wisdom attentive Buddhist
and that's why Alexa partment is a
modern tantric crazy wisdom teacher the
very polite when I must say I also want
admits his or her mistakes and inside
and so we did was that the beginning of
August we recorded civilized
conversation in a small flat in
Copenhagen we met halfway between
emminster in Stockholm any company and
had a little team a few guys who just
recorded us very simple amateurish like
you and me now we do a super chasm the
sound isn't perfect pictures the perfect
recaps there's a conversation for almost
two hours within Alexandra Bart
tantric philosopher and we let's embark
on a tantric sex ologists we're talking
about Tantra talking about sexuality
talking about sex it's different with
sexuality we talk about kracie Wister
we're talking about why we're both
working in complete and utter minefields
yes you said something that we can't why
is sex different than sexuality sex is
what you share with animals
sexuality is exclusive for Yumi's okay
so okay just just just just remember
that anything that has to do with sex
that animals would also do is sex like
the intercourse itself etc
sexuality all these crazy ideas we have
right animals do not have sexuality they
only do sex we have a sexuality and it's
never harmonious it's never about us
it's never easy it's always a minefield
and that's exactly all these Rousseau
and social justice warriors love to walk
around in sex sex and climate are the
two favorite topics because they're the
top hardest topics outfit climate right
now because it's trendy sex is always a
hot topic and always a minefield and can
never be right it can never be balanced
never harm only is always going from
that means I called Alexa Bartman when
me too started and I called our own
apartment I basically called every
Tantra guru I knew of in North America
in Europe and Asia and warned them and
said this me to thing is not gonna be
over until they gone after after every
10 to go around the planet because every
time to go at the planet has Sundy
satisfied female customer it had some
tension guru the pilot is man I didn't
become beautiful and get fucked properly
although I learn everything from my
country borders I'm gonna blame it all
on it and that's exactly what meteor was
all about bitter unfucked women in large
quantities right so I warned workmen and
then Bartman was dragged through the mud
last fall and then called me and said
listen my heart is broken people are in
love they're going after me because the
totally fucked up on this meet you thing
and and it's just a mess and you told me
this fart you warm innocent
thank you yes I warned you I won't even
happen now now we need to prepare how we
gonna have a list and what we're gonna
do next and one of the benefits of our
plan I have is that we move friends for
years intrigued and fascinated with each
other but also decided not to walk into
each other's territory so he's declared
to everybody at the team teeth in your
tongue to movement the barn is not gonna
be a member of the tundra moon we need a
few good friends outside of our
community that we can actually be in
with that could be helpful the future
that's exactly when I stupid and I
always say the same thing Department
you're not gonna be part of the men's
movement that I work with or any of the
products that are working because you do
your thing over there
I do my thing over here and by keeping
the two things separate we can maintain
a brotherhood or broster orders are
going out in friendship so we had this
conversation it's gone viral and we're
dating Ike I think I can think of a more
beautiful and fascinating woman to date
and a woman also being a man who's
fucked thousands of women and figured
out what the female mind said is like
and the only thing I'll say yeah well
it's true and I listened to that
interview I was I was impressed at how
female he was during that interview
you seemed abashed you don't see the
bastard on me or other people I can see
with him you seem kind of abashed legs
apart but it's quite a character
let us meet them they did in Brazil
already in January and that's why I got
interested uh but yeah I understand
apart but it's a controversial figure
but so am I so what no that doesn't mean
that the people who go after it's all
right no of course they're not we want
people who long and said I'm not a damn
role model mom I never wanted to be
anybody's role model I always tell
people on hendrik meaning that you know
I'm crazy and you there's no way you can
live my lifestyle it's so damn
complicated and so weird that it's gonna
freak out so don't even try okay
I'm ashamed man in the forest I'm crazy
I'm country right so they don't crazy
wisdom so is weapon that's why I think
the Donald worked and at the end of the
dollar get pointed out to Lex about them
there's one thing left for you to do
because he's basically passed on the TMT
to new generation they're building a
tented monastry in Holland where I'm an
advisor it's a brilliant product by the
way imagine you fly to Schiphol Airport
and you drive 20 minutes somewhere you
walk into a beautiful building you're
met by the world's leading most
professional cyclists are gonna fix your
sex life or you know they gonna have to
charge for that
anybody in the world should charge for
them consult there's gotta be the tented
monastry in Holland but those guys over
there
Perry's great Chris Clark or the people
who work there the young beautiful
wonderful sexist ecologist I love them
all so does work but Barber has passed
it on to them so the question was it's
worth more anything left to do as
attempt to teach and I said there's one
thing one thing that Alexa Bartman will
be the best teacher in the world and
that is to really teach women and how to
be liberated in their female sexuality I
can't think of a better teacher in the
world then having a session a closed
session for a few hours with Alexa
Markman teaching women or what it likes
to really be a woman and fully embrace
your femininity sexual and Barbara
agreed already moving there a selects
apartment
Alex farmer is not gonna teach you
longer you do not see Alexa work on
teaching women and really fully
accomplished female liberation female
sexual liberation
I can't think of a better feminist
because he goes straight to the embody
and what he's really practicing and
wants to practice is embodied feminism
terrifies man doesn't it yeah I agree I
love it I think this is contemporary
Tantra in its best possible from coming
out of crazy with some people doing
weird and crazy well if you want to role
rather than the teacher you go for Sutra
if you want to teach her you go for
somebody's really crazy wicked told me
that you have to become fully male and
fully female in the tantric path you
have to become both that's why I admire
of apartment he's really or she really
is an embodied full androgynous 100% man
while I was in woman character and works
himself or herself towards that goal
and I think it's quite amazing time I
see somebody embodying something that I
make theory I know so we'll see where
the dialogue ends I think the current as
for now that was fine like the Casa
Stern debate the beginning of the summer
I don't have anything more to say to
Custer now I'm only gonna return to him
and challenge him again when I have more
stuff to talk about
in defense of Cosmopolitan's which of
course will my artists